

## **RYAN TAN GEE TENG**

Email: <a href="mailto:ryan\_tangt@outlook.com">ryan\_tangt@outlook.com</a>

Mobile: +65 8881 6590

LinkedIn: <a href="https://bit.ly/3sJB6Z1">https://bit.ly/3sJB6Z1</a>

## **Summary of Qualifications**

Undergraduate student from National University of Singapore (NUS) with a bachelor's degree in Mechanical Engineering and Minor in Computer Science. **Graduating in June 2022**.

Highly experienced in mechanical design, 2D part drawing, and automation. Competent in robotics, simulations, and UR programming language.

Strong background on data structures and algorithms. Also proficient in Git, GitHub, software engineering and development, and Artificial Intelligence.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **National University of Singapore (NUS)**

Aug 2018 - Present

- Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering
- Dean's List of AY19/20 Semester 2
- Minor in Computer Science
- Graduating in June 2022

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Mechanical Design Engineer, Skymech Automation Pte Ltd, Singapore

Dec 2020 - May 2021

- Design innovative and specialized machines for company clients using AutoCAD and Inventor
- Utilise CAD software to create 2D drawings for special parts
- Manage project timeline and BOM
- Liaise with company clients on customized products
- Negotiating project requirements and deadlines with clients
- Presenting product ideas to prospective customers

#### Sales Promoter, Samsonite, Singapore

May 2019 – June 2019

- Cultivate relationships with prospective clients
- Achieving highest sales in sales team with an amount of \$55,000
- Manage and quantify products in stashes

#### Tour Guide, Royal Selangor Sdn Bhd, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

**April 2018 – June 2018** 

- Conduct tour guides for guests through assigned exhibit while ensuring a smooth flow of traffic
- Greet company clients and serve clients accordingly
- Provide detailed information and historical events of company

### Day care Teacher, Bright Kids Day care Centre, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Jan 2018 - June 2018

- Planned and implemented primary school curriculum
- Tracked and completed daily charts and reports for students
- Maintained strict yet friendly learning environment

## **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

#### **Community Development and Learning Project**

August 2019 - June 2020

- Review and address social issues to public
- Improve community wellness by organizing timely events

#### ME3103 Mechanical Design Project (BRONZE AWARD)

July 2020 - June 2021

- Design and improve a wheelchair to suit the needs of Cerebral Palsy patients
- Negotiate with client to achieve a product to their best interests
- Apply CAD software knowledge to simulate prototype and 3D printed parts

#### **Software Engineering Project**

Jan 2022 - Present

- Develop a brown-field project to fit target users
- Coordinate team of developers to collaborate in the project

## **Java Application Development**

Jan 2022 - March 2022

- Develop an application to track task and remind deadlines
- Utilise Git and GitHub as source control for project

## **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

#### Sub-committee Head, Green Committee, Raffles Hall

**September 2018 – May 2019** 

- Arrange various activities and events for Raffles Hall members
- Coordinate meetings and originate innovative ideas
- Spread awareness of environmental issues to public

#### **Vice Project Director of AMCISA Freshmen Orientation Camp**

**August 2019 - July 2020** 

- Organise a welcoming freshmen camp for NUS Malaysian Undergraduates
- Arrange interesting and educating activities
- Innovate creative activities that suits in an online platform

# **SKILLS**

- Autodesk Inventor
- SolidWorks
- AutoCAD
- UR (Universal Robot) programming and automation
- Familiar with Java, C, C++, Python programming languages
- GitHub

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

• Fluent in 3 languages - Chinese, English and Malay